<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>JAMS on Eric&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://ericcsinger.com/tags/jams/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JAMS on Eric&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>©2025, Eric C. Singer
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 21:20:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ericcsinger.com/tags/jams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review: 1.5 years with MVP Systems Job Automation Scheduler (JAMS)</title>
      <link>https://ericcsinger.com/review-1.5-years-with-mvp-systems-job-automation-scheduler-jams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 21:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ericcsinger.com/review-1.5-years-with-mvp-systems-job-automation-scheduler-jams/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="introduction" data-numberify>Introduction:<a class="anchor ms-1" href="#introduction"></a></h1>
<p>I wrote a really quick review <a href="http://wp.me/p62gzE-1W" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here<i class="fas fa-external-link-square-alt ms-1"></i></a> about MVP systems JAMS product about 1 year or so ago (maybe a little less). At the time, I was in search of a solution that could help me glue together several disjointed systems in a workflow. Specifically, we were trying to integrate Veeam and CommVault backup’s together. Veeam was of course doing the VM backup’s, and CommVault was copying the Veeam files to tape. We’ve since moved on from Veeam, but JAMS has continued to be a vital part of our infrastructure.</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving: CommVault tape usage</title>
      <link>https://ericcsinger.com/problem-solving-commvault-tape-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 23:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ericcsinger.com/problem-solving-commvault-tape-usage/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="introduction" data-numberify>Introduction:<a class="anchor ms-1" href="#introduction"></a></h1>
<p>I hate dealing with tapes, pretty much every aspect of them. The tracking of them is a PITA, having to physically manage them is a PITA, dealing with tape library issues is a PITA, dealing with tape encryption is a PITA, running out of tapes is a PITA, dealing with legal hold for tapes is a PITA, and I could keep going on with the many ways that tape just sucks. What makes matters worse is when you have to deal with MORE tapes.</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving: Chasing SQL&#39;s Dump</title>
      <link>https://ericcsinger.com/problem-solving-chasing-sqls-dump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 19:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ericcsinger.com/problem-solving-chasing-sqls-dump/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-problem" data-numberify>The Problem:<a class="anchor ms-1" href="#the-problem"></a></h1>
<p>For years as an admin I’ve had to deal with SQL. At a former employer, our SQL environment / databases were small, and backup licensing was based on agents, not capacity. Fast forward to my current employer, we have a fairly decent sized SQL environment (60 – 70 servers), our backup’s are large , licensing is based on capacity, and we have a full time DBA crew that manage their own backup schedules, and prefer that backup’s are managed by them. What that means is dealing with a ton of dumps. Read into that as you want 🙂</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

